BRIAN LYNCH



○ DETAILS ○

+353 879366009 BrianLynch182@gmail.com

∘ LINKS ∘

Personal Website

Github - BrianLunch

<u>LinkedIn</u>

o SKILLS o

ECDL - Microsft Office Cert ReactJS

Dafne

Java

Prolog

С

Arm Assembly

HTML & CSS

JavaScript

Github Proficiency

Haskell

Analytical Thinking

Collaboration & Teamwork

Computer Hardware Knowledge

ReactJS

Microsoft Azure

AWS

Cloud Computing

Direct Sales

∘ HOBBIES ∘

I play football for Trinitys Collegiate team in Irelands top college division.

I also play Gaelic football for my local team.

I am also a member of Trinitys Computer Science society, DUCSS and enjoy attending their events.

∘ REFERENCES ∘

Damien Foley

Head of Cloud Centre of Excellence

Damien.Foley@zurich.com +353 (0) 1 799 2894

Gavin Doherthy

Java Project Lecturer

gavin.doherty@tcd.ie +353 1896 3858

PROFILE

I am a final year computer science student in Trinity College Dublin. I am currently on track to graduate with a distinction (1.1) in my degree and have thoroughly enjoyed every moment of it. I have great problem solving skills and work very well under pressure. I have experience working with numerous technologies both academically and professionally including a cloud computing internship in Zurich Insurance plc.

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

WEB DEVELOPMENT as a Freelancer

May 2018 - Present

- Actively engage with clients using upwork and other feelancing sites.
- Identify the clients needs and discuss their brands identity.
- Use the most applicable language/framework to build their site.
- Produce the client with a professional, functional & aesthetically pleasing website.

PROGRAMMING TEACHING ASSISTANT - JAVA at Trinity College Dublin, Dublin, Ireland.

January 2020 - Present

This position was assigned to me based on my current grades (GPA). The role involved:

- Coaching groups of first year students in their learning of Java.
- · Providing students with weekly goals based on their current progress and ability.
- Grading their programming projects weekly and providing constructive feedback.
- Supporting them with any issues that arise within their group or their program.

CLOUD COMPUTING INTERN at Zurich Insurance Plc, Dublin

May 2019 - September 2019

- Worked as part of a large global team.
- Engaged in weekly meetings and updated coworkers on my progress and new ideas.
- Built, maintained, patched and logged all servers in Zurich's private cloud.
- Supported clients on any issues via email and calls.
- Helped team members with Azure and AWS tasks.

EDUCATION

Trinity College Dublin, Dublin

September 2017 - Present

Degree: Integrated Computer Science - Level 8

I currently have a **1.1** average and have completed modules in entrepreneurship, multiple programming languages and mathematics. I have completed presentations in front of hundreds of students and worked hard throughout.

EXPERIENCE

TCDexams.com, Website

September 2020 - Present

Myself and a colleague are developing a website where trinity students can access past exams easier as we found the
current website outdated and difficult to use.

Software Engineering Team Project, UI Web Design

January 2019 - May 2019

A website which displays changes to the wikidata API and flags suspicious edits along with providing a dashbpard of
useful graphics. Accepted into the Voila '20 academic conference.

Software Engineering Team Project, Android App Dev

January 2019 - May 2019

• An android app that periodically gather information about nearby Bluetooth devices. I worked on the UI and helped with the use of the bluetooth technology.

Log On and Learn Mentor, Community Initiative

January 2016 - June 2016

An initiative in my local school which taught older people how to use technology by assigning a mentor to help them
over a 5 month period.